The world will be watching.
The Hunger Games is a science fiction, adventure,
action film directed by Gary Ross.
In a dystopian society where the Capitol forces each district to send two young tributes to fight to the death in a televised
spectacle, a girl volunteers to take her sister’s place, setting the stage for a struggle of survival and defiance.
Katniss Everdeen, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
Peeta Mellark, played by Josh Hutcherson.
Gale Hawthorne, played by Liam Hemsworth.
Haymitch Abernathy, played by Woody Harrelson.
Effie Trinket, played by Elizabeth Banks.
Cinna, played by Lenny Kravitz.
The Hunger Games is a 2012 American dystopian action film directed by Gary Ross, who co-wrote the
screenplay with Suzanne Collins and Billy Ray, based on the 2008 novel of the same name by Collins.
It is the first installment in The Hunger Games film series.
The film stars Jennifer Lawrence, Josh Hutcherson, Liam Hemsworth, Woody Harrelson,
Elizabeth Banks, Lenny Kravitz, Stanley Tucci, and Donald Sutherland.
In the film, Katniss Everdeen (Lawrence) and Peeta Mellark (Hutcherson) are forced to compete in the Hunger Games, an
elaborate televised fight to the death consisting of adolescent contestants from the 12 districts of Panem.
Development of a film adaptation of Collins' original novel began in March 2009 when Lionsgate entered into a
co-production agreement with Color Force, which had acquired the rights a few weeks earlier.
As the novel is written in Katniss' first-person point of view, its
screenplay develops ancillary characters and locations for the film.
Ross was confirmed as director in November 2010 and the rest
of the main cast was rounded out by May 2011.
Principal photography began that month and ended that September,
with filming primarily taking place in North Carolina.
The Hunger Games premiered at the Nokia Theatre in Los Angeles on March 12, 2012,
and was released in the United States on March 23, by Lionsgate.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise for its themes and messages, Lawrence's performance, and
faithfulness to the source material, although there was some criticism for its use of shaky cam and editing.
It grossed $695.2 million, setting the then-records for both the opening day and opening
weekend gross for a non-sequel, becoming the ninth-highest-grossing film of 2012.
Among its accolades, the song "Safe & Sound" from the soundtrack, performed by Taylor Swift and The Civil
Wars, won a Grammy Award and was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song.
For her performance, Lawrence won the Saturn Award for Best Actress, the Broadcast Film Critics Association Award for Best Actress in an Action
Movie, the Empire Award for Best Actress, and was also nominated for the New York Film Critics Circle Award for Best Actress.
The sequel, The Hunger Games: Catching Fire, premiered in 2013.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
revolution, dystopia, monarchy, female protagonist.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.